

% http://sarakhatri.github.io/

### SUMMARY

I am an economics-major-turned-designer with over four years of experience creating user-centered product solutions with an iterative approach. I am looking for an opportunity within the world of software design to apply my skills and experience as a product designer to build products that improve users' lives.

## **EDUCATION**

#### EDX MICROMASTERS - USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCH & DESIGN

University of Michigan I 2016-2017

I completed a series of online courses that covered topics on how to better understand user needs and how human behavior impacts the experience. The topics included usability testing, design principles, and approaches to research on user experience.

#### UX/UI DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP

Bloc, Inc. | 2015

I was an apprentice to the lead designer of Shopify during which I developed a solid understanding of user-centered design principles. I completed five projects with responsibilities ranging from branding to conceptualization to frontend development.

## B.A. ECONOMICS

University of Michigan | 2011-2014

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **UX RESEARCHER**

# Owens Corning | Feb 2018-Present

In an agile framework, I created & executed UX research plans including information architecture validation, usability testing, user requirements gathering, & other research strategies aimed at evaluating and improving UX. I communicated learnings from user research to design, development, & business teams in ways that effectively advocated for user needs. I converted research insights into tangible outcomes including wireframes and low/high fidelity mockups.

## PRODUCT DESIGN INTERN

Parabol | Sept 2017-Jan 2018

As an intern at a fast-paced startup, I contributed to the creation of the company's product (SaaS) through design collaboration, UX artifact creation, prototype testing, user research experiment design, user testing, survey design, churn analysis, A/B testing, and product strategy planning.

# FREELANCE DESIGNER

### Sara Khatri Designs | Apr 2016-Present

I worked with various clients including nonprofits, educational institutes, and startups on a variety of design projects ranging from graphic design to website design/development (HTML/CSS) to software design (UX/UI). I have experience creating UX artifacts such as sitemaps, wireframes, and low/high fidelity mockups.